Guide to the Victor H. Bassett papers, 1789-1938 and undated, bulk 1915-1938
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Victor H. Bassett papers 1789-1938 and undated bulk 1915-1938
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Bassett, Victor H.
0.5 Linear Feet 762 Items
Physician and librarian of the Georgia Medical Society of Savannah.
Public health information, including correspondence, health and mortality records, biographical information, genealogies, reports, and printed matter. Material on the medical history of Savannah and Georgia from ca. 1800 to 1939, chiefly for the period following 1915. Sketches of prominent Georgia physicians, genealogical data on some Savannah families, and data on several medical colleges, including at the University of Pennsylvania.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Victor H. Bassett papers were acquired by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 1952.
Biographical Note
Victor Bassett was a physician and librarian of the Georgia Medical Society of Savannah.
Collection Overview
Papers collected by a physician and librarian of the Georgia Medical Society relating to public health in Georgia, including Savannah; Georgia physicians; midwives; smallpox inoculation; University of Pennsylvania medical instruction in the early 19th Century; Federal Emergency Relief Administration employment for nurses; and Works Progress Administration (WPA) malaria control projects. Included are letters, reports, extracts, articles, charts, lists, photos, and genealogical data on the McAllister and White families of Pennsylvania and the Le Conte and Habersham families of Georgia. There is also a journal of J. J. Waring and Joseph Frederick Waring in London, Dublin, and Paris, 1853-1855. Writers of correspondence include William Gibbons, Horace Senter, David Ramsey, John C. Warren, John Le Conte, and T. F. Abercrombie.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Bassett, Victor H.
University of Pennsylvania. School of Medicine -- History
Malaria -- Georgia -- History
Medical education -- United States -- History
Public health -- Georgia -- Savannah -- History
Physicians -- Georgia -- Savannah
Smallpox vaccination -- United States -- History
Georgia -- Social conditions
Georgia -- Genealogy
Savannah (Ga.) -- Social conditions
Photographs
Contents of Collection
- Victor H. Bassett papers, 1789-1938 (bulk 1915-1938), (8 boxes)
  - Papers, 1789-1928 (Box 1)
  - Papers, 1929-1935 (Box 2)
  - Papers, 1936-1938 and undated (Box 3)
  - Papers, undated, and Articles by Walter J. Hoxie (Box 4)
  - Papers (Lecture Notes), 1891-1892, 1901 and undated (Box 5)
  - Papers (Lecture Notes), 1901 and undated (Box 6)
  - Papers (Lecture Notes), 1901-1902 (Box 7)
  - Papers (Articles by Walter J. Hoxie) (Box 8)
  - Papers (clippings and printed material) (Box 8)
  - Photographs (Box 8)